Guide to the Carlsark Collection, ca. 1920-1973.
Carlsark Collection, ca. 1920-1973
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carlsark collection, ca. 1920-1973.
1145
1.8 cubic ft.
Logbooks, a scrapbook, newspaper clippings, printed material, photographs, maps, and a wooden model.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Included are five logbooks kept by Carl Weagant during the Carlsark's voyage to Greece and back (1929-30), as well as a log kept by Henry Devereux. Also, a scrapbook of newspaper clippings; printed material, including articles by Weagant and Devereux, Yacht Club yearbooks, and other items; photographs of the Carlsark and her crew; hand made maps of voyages made by the Carlsark and other boats; and a wooden model of the Carlsark.
The CARLSARK was a yacht owned by Carl L. Weagant, who sailed from Ithaca, New York, to Ithaca, Greece, shortly after graduating from Cornell University in 1929. The other crew members were Henry M. Devereux, Joseph Rummler, and Dudley Schoales. Weagant later wrote for YACHTING magazine and invested in salvage projects. In 1934, he committed suicide, citing financial failure as the reason in a note to his family.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Included are five logbooks kept by Carl Weagant during the CARLSARK's voyage to Greece and back (1929-30), as well as a log kept by Henry Devereux. Also, a scrapbook of newspaper clippings; printed material, including articles by Weagant and Devereux, Yacht Club yearbooks, and other items; photographs of the CARLSARK and her crew; hand made maps of voyages made by the CARLSARK and other boats; and a wooden model of the CARLSARK.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Devereux, Henry M.; Rummler, Joseph.; Schoales, Dudley.; Weagant, Carl L.; Carlsark (Yacht).
Titles:
Yachting.
Subjects:
Voyages and travels.; Yachts and yachting.; Sailors.
Places:
Ithakē (Greece)--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Maps.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Log Book, Volume 1, from Ithaca, N.Y. to the Azores Islands, June 20, 1929-Aug. 2, 1929 (Box 1)
- Log Book, Volume 2, from Aorta, Fayal, Azores to the French Riviera, Aug. 7, 1929-Sept. 10, 1929 (Box 1)
- Log Book, Volume 3, from departure from Cannes on French Riviera; episodes at the island of Ithaca, Greece; through arrival at Gibralter on the return trip home, Nov. 27, 1929-Jan.12, 1930 (Box 1)
- Log Book, Volume 4, from departure from Gibralter and arrival at Nassau, Bahamas, Feb. 4, 1930-Apr. 12, 1930 (Box 1)
- Log Book, Volume 5, from Nassau, Bahamas to the North Carolina Islands, May 14, 1930-May 19, 1930 (Box 1)
- Henry Devereux's Note Book, from early part of August much of this is duplicated of the orginal log. Not shown in the original log are additional notes from the Azores, and Devereux's subsequent trip to Boston and New York, June 20, 1929-Aug. 20, 1929 (Box 1)
- Blue water medal presented to Carl Weagant by the Crusing Club of America, 1930 (Box 1)
- Typescript re: the "Carlsark", n.d. (Box 2)
- Printed articles, excerpts, etc, ca. 1920-1973 (Box 2)
- Photocopied articles from Yachting, Dec. 1929; Jan., Nov., Dec. 1930; Jan.-May 1931 (Box 2)
- Yachting magazine in which articles regarding the Carlsbad trip appear, June 1931; Mar. 1933; Feb., July; Aug., Nov., Dec. 1934; Apr. (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of clippings, blueprints, and memorabilia pertaining to the Carlsark, 1929-1934 (Box 3)
- Bayside Yacht Club Log Book, Apr. 1925 (Box 3)
- Royal Ocean Racing Club booklet., 1925-1934 (Box 3)
- The Crusing Club of America yearbook, 1934 (Box 3)
- The Yachtsmans Yearbook edited by Alfred F. Loomis (dedicated to Mrs. R.A. Weagant), 1934 (Box 3)
- Blue Water Vagabond by Denis Puleston, 1939 (Box 3)
- Map of the "Bermuda Race, 1926, on Board Schooner Countess" (Box 4)
- Map of "The Cruise of the Carlsark", 1926-1930 (Box 4)
- Small map of the Carlsark voyage, 1929 (Box 4)
- Map of "The Cruise of the Pinta", ca. 1931 (Box 4)
- Photocopies of entries in the Carlsark Log Book concerning Christmas Eve in Palermo, 1929 (Box 4)
- Model of the Carlsark, Mu. 916